Norman H. Davis Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence and Other Papers, 1918-1942 (Box 1-71)
  - Paris Peace Conference (Box 43)
    - American Economic Group, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Brussels Conference, 1919-1920 (Box 46)
    - Financial Commission, 1919 (Box 46)
    - International labor legislation, commission reports, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Library, American Commission], 1919 (Box 46)
    - Liquidation and Readjustment Commission, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Mission file, 1919 (Box 47)
    - Neutral Financiers, Neutral Finance Committee, 1919 (Box 47)
    - Par of exchange, 1919 (Box 47)
    - Reports of committees, 1919 (Box 47)
    - Rhineland Territory, Inter-allied Commission, 1919 (Box 47)
    - Shipping, 1919 (Box 47)
    - Superior Blockade Council, 1919 (Box 47)
  - Peace awards, 1924 (Box 47)
  - Pell, Robert, 1935-1939 (Box 47)
  - Phillips, William, 1920-1939 (Box 47)
  - Pittman, Key, 1922-1936 (Box 47)
  - Poison Gas Protocol of 1925, 1925 (Box 47)
  - Polk, Frank L, 1920-1942, (2 folders) (Box 47)
  - Quinn, C. W., 1919-1921 (Box 47)
  - "R" cross-reference sheets (Box 47)
  - "R" miscellaneous (Box 47)
  - Rathbone, Albert, 1919-1937 (Box 48)
  - Red Cross, 1919 (Box 48)
  - Reparations, 1919-1923 (Box 48)
    - Minutes of Post-War Reparations Committee (Box 48)
      - Nos. 1-31 with certain numbers missing, as listed on folders, 1921, Jan. 24-Mar. 29, (2 folders) (Box 48)
      - Nos. 32-124 with certain numbers missing, as listed on folders, 1920, Mar. 31-1921, Jan. 7, (4 folders) (Box 49)
    - Legal opinions (Box 50)
      - 1920, (3 folders) (Box 50)
      - New series, circa 1920 (Box 51)
      - Old series, etc., circa 1920 (Box 51)
      - Second subcommittee, 1919 (Box 51)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1922-1941 (Box 51)
  - Royal Bank of Canada (C. E. Neill), 1920-1921 (Box 51)
  - Russia, embassy in United States, 1920-1921 (Box 52)
  - Russian Student Fund (Box 52)
    - 1921-1930, (5 folders) (Box 52)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 53)
  - "S" cross-reference sheets (Box 53)
  - "S" miscellaneous (Box 53)
  - Salter, Sir Arthur, 1928-1932 (Box 53)
  - Shotwell, James T., 1925-1942 (Box 53)
  - Silver, 1931 (Box 53)
  - Simon, Sir John, 1932 (Box 53)
  - Social Security Act, 1938 (Box 53)
  - Spain, 1937 (Box 53)
  - Speyer, James 1932 (Box 53)
  - Standard Oil Co., 1920-1921 (Box 53)
  - State Department (Box 53)
    - 1928-1929 (Box 53)
    - 1938-1942 (2 folders) (Box 54)
    - Addresses, statements, memoranda, and press releases, 1937-1941 (Box 54)
  - Steinhardt, Lawrence, 1934 (Box 54)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1931-1936 (Box 54)
  - Streit, Clarence, 1934-1942 (Box 54)
  - Sugar Conference (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1937, Mar. 24-May 15 (Box 55)
    - General, 1937, Mar.- Apr (Box 55)
    - Official correspondence, memoranda, 1937, Apr. (Box 55)
    - Conversation memoranda, 1937, Apr.-May (Box 55)
    - Statements and agreements, 1937, Apr.-May (Box 55)
  - Supreme Economic Council (Box 56)
    - General, 1919 (Box 56)
    - Proceedings, 1919, Feb.-Sept, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - Mainly minutes and agendas, 1919, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 56, Box 57)
    - Proceedings, financial subcommission, 1919 (Box 57)
    - Finance Section, minutes, 1919, (3 folders) (Box 58, Box 59)
      - Financial meeting at Treves, France, 1919, (3 folders) (Box 60)
      - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 60)
        - Mar.-Apr. (Box 60)
        - May-June, (2 folders) (Box 61)
      - Correspondence between Finance Section and German Finance Commission 1919-1920 (Box 61)
    - Papers arising out of deposits of german gold for food, 1919 (Box 61)
    - Duplicates of German letters and translations, 1919 (Box 61)
    - Miscellaneous, 1919 (Box 61)
  - Sweetser, Arthur, 1919-1940, (3 folders) (Box 62)
  - "T" cross-reference sheets (Box 62)
  - "T" miscellaneous (Box 62)
  - Taussig, F. W., 1919-1924 (Box 62)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1936-1941 (Box 62)
  - Trade and tariff, 1937 (Box 62)
  - Treasury Department (Box 62)
    - 1919-1921 (Box 62)
    - Russian inquiries, 1935 (Box 62)
  - Trust Co. of Cuba, 1918-1921 (Box 63)
  - Tumulty, Joseph P., 1919-1921 (Box 63)
  - "U" miscellaneous (Box 63)
  - "V' cross-reference sheets (Box 63)
  - "V" miscellaneous (Box 63)
  - Versailles Treaty See Containers 43-47, Paris Peace Conference (Box 63)
  - "W" cross-reference sheets (Box 63)
  - "Wa-Wh" miscellaneous (Box 63)
  - War debts, 1932-1937, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Welles, Sumner, 1921-1942, (2 folders) (Box 63)
  - Whitner, W. M. (Box 64)
    - 1920-1926, (4 folders) (Box 64)
    - 1929, Jan.-July (Box 64)
    - 1929, Aug.-Dec. (Box 65)
    - 1930-1931, (3 folders) (Box 65)
  - Hartford Fire Insurance Co., 1916-1926 (Box 66)
  - Insurance, Royal Bank and Trust Co. of Cuba, 1917-1918 (Box 66)
  - Home Insurance Company, circa 1917-1926 (Box 66)
  - Insurance Agencies Corp., circa 1919-1926 July 1, (3 folders) (Box 66)
  - Johnson and Higgins, 1923 (Box 66)
  - Meidlinger, Charles R., circa 1916-1918 (Box 66)
  - Pedroso agreement and correspondence, 1925 (Box 66)
  - Phoenix Insurance Co., 1918 (Box 66)
  - Purchase of Insurance Agency from Royal Bank of Canada, 1920-1922 (Box 66)
  - Sanborn Map Co., 1920 (Box 66)
  - Workman's Compensation Law and Tariffs (Box 66)
  - Whitner, W. M. and Insurance Agencies Corp., circa 1919-1931, (2 folders) (Box 66)
  - "Wi-Wy" miscellaneous (Box 67)
  - Wickersham, George W., 1922-1935 (Box 67)
  - Wilson, Hugh R. 1932-1941 (Box 67)
  - Wilson, Woodrow (Box 67)
    - 1919-1924; 1929, (2 folders) (Box 67)
    - Memorial service, printed tributes, etc., 1924 (Box 68)
    - Memorials, 1937-1942, (2 folders) (Box 68)
  - Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt, 1924-1933 (Box 68)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation (Box 68)
    - 1921-1924 (Box 68)
    - 1925-1928, (4 folders) (Box 69)
    - 1929-1937, (6 folders) (Box 70)
    - Contemplated Bok Award, 1926-1928, (2 folders) (Box 71)
    - Investments, 1926 (Box 71)
    - Securities, 1926-1928 (Box 71)
    - Finance Committee, 1931-1932 (Box 71)
  - Woolley, Mary E., 1921-1936 (Box 71)
  - "Y" miscellaneous (Box 71)
  - Young, Owen D., 1921-1930 (Box 71)
- Printed Matter, 1933-1937 (Box 72-76)
  Mainly newspaper clippings relating to international trade and finance, and to international conferences.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Armaments, 1935-1936 (Box 72)
  - Debts, 1933, (2 folders) (Box 72)
  - Disarmament (Box 72)
    - 1933, Jan.-Sept., (5 folders) (Box 72)
    - 1933, Sept.-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 73)
    - 1934, Mar.-June (Box 73)
    - 1935, Jan. (Box 73)
  - Economic Conference, 1933 (Box 74)
  - London Naval Conference (Box 74)
    - 1935, Dec.-1936, Feb., (5 folders) (Box 74)
    - 1936, Mar.-May, (2 folders) (Box 75)
  - Naval (Box 75)
    - 1934, Oct.-Dec., (5 folders) (Box 75)
    - 1935-1937, (2 folders) (Box 75)
  - Neutrality, 1935-1937, (3 folders) (Box 76)
  - Trade, 1937 (Box 76)
- Addition I, 1915-1945 (Box 77-92)
  Financial papers, subject files, correspondence, printed matter, and newspaper clippings
  Mostly arranged alphabetically by topic. Some files arranged by type of material.
  - Kreuger Group (Box 77)
    - Plans, reports, and statements (Box 77)
    - Plans, reports, and statements (Box 78)
    - Miscellany (Box 79)
  - Kreuger & Toll (Box 79)
    - 1927-1934 (Box 79)
    - 1935 (Box 80)
    - Miscellany (Box 80)
    - Printed matter relating to Charles E.Coughlin attack (Box 80)
  - Kreuger Group (Box 81)
    - Plans, reports, and statements (Box 81)
      - 1933-1934 (Box 81)
      - 1933-1935 (Box 82)
    - Memoranda and printed matter (Box 83)
  - Millett-Roe financial papers, 1928-1932 (Box 84)
  - J. P. Morgan & Co., financial papers and correspondence, 1930-1934 (Box 85)
  - Seaboard Airline Railroad, financial papers and correspondence (Box 86)
    - 1930-1934 (Box 86)
    - 1930-1934 (Box 87)
    - 1930-1934 (Box 88)
  - Bank statements (Box 89)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and pamphlets on Geneva, Switzerland, 1933 (Box 90)
  - Report on Cuba sugar industries, 1915, 1924-1925 (Box 90)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1932-1938 (Box 91)
  - Diary, 1921 (Box 92)
  - Cable correspondence relating to john Maynard Keynes plan 1919, Apr. 26-May 27 (Box 92)
  - Correspondence realting to financial reconstruction, 1919, Mar. 30-May 16, 1919 (Box 92)
  - Correspondence, 1920, Apr. 11-Nov. 15 (Box 92)
  - Notes taken during Paris Peace Conference, 1919 (Box 92)
  - Miscellany (Box 92)
- Addition II, 1918-1960 (Box 93-94)
  Subject files on the Peace Commission and miscellaneous correspondence, writings, notes, printed matter, clippings, and other material..
  Arranged by topic.
  - Correspondence, 1918-1947 (Box 93)
  - Notebook, message of Davis to his children, prayers and poems, and copies of letters of condolence on the death of Mrs. Davis, 1942, Mar. (Box 93)
  - Book manuscript, "Mission to Memel-1924," Chapter VII (Box 93)
  - Writing fragments (Box 93)
  - Notes (Box 93)
  - Articles and radio address relating to Davis (Box 93)
  - Photographs (Box 93)
  - Miscellany (Box 93)
  - Printed matter, general (Box 93)
  - Clippings (Box 93)
  - Peace Commission material, 1919, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 93, Box 94)
  - Scrapbooks, 1920-1940 See Oversize (Box 94)
- Addition III, 1898-1979 (Box 95-99)
  Correspondence, speeches and writings, subject files, printed matter, and photographs.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or topic.
  - American Club of Havana, Havana, Cuba 1936 (Box 95)
  - Chronological file, 1921-1944, undated See also Classified, (2 folders) (Box 95)
  - Correspondence (Box 95)
    - Davis, Mackie Paschall (wife) (Box 95)
      - 1913-1916, (5 folders) (Box 95)
      - 1917 (Box 95)
        - June (Box 95)
        - July-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 96)
      - 1918 (Box 96)
        - Aug.-Dec., (2 folders) (Box 96)
      - 1920-1924, (2 folders) (Box 96)
    - General (Box 96)
      - 1898, 1917-1924 (Box 96)
      - 1925-1938, 1957-1958, undated, (6 folders) (Box 97)
    - Hull, Cordell 1922-1946, (2 folders) (Box 97)
  - General Disarmament Conference, Geneva, Switzerland (Box 97)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1935 (Box 97)
    - "Norman H. Davis, Diary and Memoranda of Conversations," 1932, Jan.-Aug. (Box 97)
    - Nous Desarmons ..., 1932 (Box 97)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box 98)
  - National Archives, Washington, D. C., preliminary inventories (Box 98)
    - Records of United States Participation in International Conferences, Commissions, and Expositions, 1955 (Box 98)
    - Records of the American Commission to Negotiate Peace, 1955 (Box 98)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1920-1979 (Box 98)
  - New York University School of Law, New York, N.Y., honorary doctor of law, 1938 (Box 98)
  - Photographs 1943, undated See Oversize (Box 98)
  - Printed matter 1924-1926 (Box 98)
  - Record of Informal and Confidential Memoranda and Conferences Dealing with Reparation Clauses of Conditions of Peace, 1919, (2 folders) (Box 98)
  - Speeches and writings (Box 98)
    - By Davis (Box 98)
      - Draft articles about the League of Nations, 1928 (Box 98)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 98)
        - 1919-1924 (Box 98)
        - 1925-1943, undated, (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - By others, 1922-1968 (Box 99)
- Oversize, 1920-1943 (Box OV 1-OV 4)
  Scrapbooks and photographs.
  Arranged and described according to the series, container, and file from which the matter was removed.
  - Addition II (Box OV 1)
    - Scrapbooks (Box OV 1)
      - 1920-1921 (Container 94), (2 vols.) (Box OV 1)
      - 1931-1936 (Container 94), (3 vols.) (Box OV 2)
      - 1937, Sugar Conference (Container 94) (Box OV 3)
      - 1937, Brussels Conference (Container 94) (Box OV 3)
      - 1938-1940 (Container 94) (Box OV 3)
    - Photographs, 1943, undated (Container 98) (Box OV 4)
- Classified, 1927-1935 (Box CL 1)
  Documents containing national security information removed from the collection.
  Arranged and described according to the series and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Addition III (Box CL 1)
    - Chronological file (Box CL 1)
      - Meeting notes, Naval Conference, 1935 (Container 95) (Box CL 1)
      - Summary of information received to a telegraphic circular concerning attitude of foreign government toward the Economic Conference 1927, Mar. 7 (Container 95) (Box CL 1)